Richard York Gallery
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Business and Financial Records, 1974-2005, Series 6:; (Boxes 70-77; 6.25 linear feet)
  - Business Records, 1974-2005, 6.1:
    - 21 East 65th Street Lease, 1989-1990 (Box 70, Folder 29)
    - Acordia Northeast (Fine Arts Dealers Insurance), 1997-2000 (Box 70, Folder 30)
    - Acordia Northeast, Certificates of Insurance, 1998-2004 (Box 70, Folder 31)
    - Acordia Northeast, Certificates of Insurance, 2001 (Box 70, Folder 32)
    - ADAA (Art Dealer's Association of America), 1994, 1998-1999 (Box 70, Folder 33)
    - ADAA Appraisal Materials, 2002 (Box 70, Folder 34)
    - ADAA Art Show Selection Policy, 2003 (Box 70, Folder 35)
    - ADAA Board of Directors and Executive Committee Meeting Minutes, 1998-2000 (Box 70, Folder 36)
    - ADAA Board of Directors Meeting (April 21, 1999), 1999 (Box 70, Folder 37)
    - ADAA Board of Directors Meeting (October 5, 1999), 1999 (Box 70, Folder 38)
    - ADAA Board of Directors Meeting (February 2000), circa 2000 (Box 70, Folder 39)
    - ADAA Board of Directors and Executive Committee Meetings (February 28, 2000), 2000 (Box 71, Folder 1)
    - ADAA Board of Directors and Executive Committee Meetings (April 27, 2000), 2000 (Box 71, Folder 2)
    - ADAA Board of Directors Meeting (September 12, 2000), 2000 (Box 71, Folder 3)
    - ADAA Board of Directors Meeting (November 6, 2001), 2001 (Box 71, Folder 4)
    - ADAA By-Laws, 1989 (Box 71, Folder 5)
    - ADAA Committee Members, circa 1998-2000 (Box 71, Folder 6)
    - ADAA Executive Committee Meeting (August 27, 1998), 1998 (Box 71, Folder 7)
    - ADAA Executive Committee Meeting (April 20, 1999), 1999 (Box 71, Folder 8)
    - ADAA Membership Committee, 2001 (Box 71, Folder 9)
    - ADAA Membership Committee Meeting (September 11, 2001), 2001 (Box 71, Folder 10)
    - ADAA Membership Committee Meeting (January 29, 2003), 2003 (Box 71, Folder 11)
    - ADAA Membership Directory, 2000 (Box 71, Folder 12)
    - ADAA Membership Fall 2001, 2001 (Box 71, Folder 13)
    - Advertising, Online, 2000 (Box 71, Folder 14)
    - Appraisers Association of America, 1981-1985 (Box 71, Folder 15)
    - Artbase 5 CD and Image Files, circa 2002-2004, (2 CDs) (Box 71, Folder 16)
    - ArtBase 5 Manual, circa 2002 (Box 71, Folder 17)
    - Artists' Biographies: Frank Anderson, 1989 (Box 71, Folder 18)
    - Artists' Biographies: William Bliss Baker, 1989 (Box 71, Folder 19)
    - Artists' Biographies: John Marin, circa 1998-2000 (Box 71, Folder 20)
    - Artists' Biographies: John Singer Sargent, circa 1981-2004 (Box 71, Folder 21)
    - Artists' Biographies: Joseph Stella, circa 1990 (Box 71, Folder 22)
    - Artists' Biographies: Steve Wheeler, circa 1998-1999 (Box 71, Folder 23)
    - Artwork Information Sheets and American Express Receipts, circa 1981-2004 (Box 71, Folder 24)
    - Authentications: John Marin, 2003 (Box 71, Folder 25)
    - Bank Account Information, circa 1990s-2000s (Box 71, Folder 26)
    - Bookstores, 2005 (Box 71, Folder 27)
    - Business Contacts, circa 1990s-2000s (Box 71, Folder 28)
    - Christmas Party, circa 2002 (Box 71, Folder 29)
    - Client Interest Codes, circa 2000 (Box 71, Folder 30)
    - Closing Accounts, 2004, April-May (Box 71, Folder 31)
    - Contacts, B-O, 1974-1991, (shoebox) (Box 71, Folder 32)
    - Contacts, P-Z, Miscellaneous, 1974-1991, (shoebox) (Box 71, Folder 33)
    - Curriculum Vitae, Richard York, circa 1999 (Box 72, Folder 1)
    - Donations, 2004 (Box 72, Folder 2)
    - Exhibition: "Drawings and Watercolors by John William Hill" (April 11-May 10, 2003), 2003 (Box 72, Folder 3)
    - Exhibition: "Great Planes" (Nov 8-Dec 20, 2002), circa 2002 (Box 72, Folder 4)
    - Exhibition: Lester Hornby (March 20 - April 14, 1984), 1983-1984 (Box 72, Folder 5)
    - Exhibition: "Marin in Maine," Colby College (Aug 13 - Sept 12, 1992), 1998 (Box 72, Folder 6)
    - Exhibition: Masterworks Foundation, Bermuda Exhibition (April 14-May 26, 2000), 2000 (Box 72, Folder 7)
    - Guest Book, 1981-1982, 1995 (Box 72, Folder 8)
    - Insurance; Norman Newman, Polar International Brokerage, 1983-1985 (Box 72, Folder 9)
    - Mailing Lists, circa 1981-1985 (Box 72, Folder 10)
    - Mailing Lists, 1983-1984 (Box 72, Folder 11)
    - Mailing Lists, circa 1985 (Box 72, Folder 12)
    - Manhattan Mini Storage, 2000 (Box 72, Folder 13)
    - Manuals, circa 1995 (Box 72, Folder 14)
    - Marin, John; Lopez Restoration List for "The Line That Lives" (May 2003), 2003 (Box 72, Folder 15)
    - Miscellaneous, circa 1990s-2004 (Box 72, Folder 16)
    - Obituaries and Memorial for Richard York, 2003 (Box 72, Folder 17)
    - Palm Pilots, 2001 (Box 72, Folder 18)
    - Public Relations, 2Bridge Communications, 2002 (Box 72, Folder 19)
    - Research [Richard York's Art Collection], 1997-2001 (Box 72, Folder 20)
    - Research Cards for Reference, 1982-1995 (Box 72, Folder 21)
    - Richard T. York Photograph Collection, 1996-1998 (Box 72, Folder 22)
    - Richard T. York Photograph Collection, Insurance, 1997-1998 (Box 72, Folder 23)
    - Richard T. York Photograph Collection, Robert Mapplethorpe, 1997-2000, (2 folders) (Box 72, Folder 24-25)
    - Richard T. York Photograph Collection, Mapplethorpes On Loan, 2002 (Box 72, Folder 26)
    - RTY American Art, Inc., 1989-1990 (Box 72, Folder 27)
    - RTY American Art, Inc. Corporate Records, 1989-1990, (2 folders, disassembled binder, includes metal seal press) (Box 72, Folder 28-29)
    - RTY Fine Arts, Inc., Corporate Records, 1980-1991, 2000, (2 folders, disassembled binder, includes metal seal press) (Box 72, Folder 30-31)
    - Shipping Records (January-March 2000), 1999-2000 (Box 73, Folder 1)
    - Shipping Records (April-May 2000), 2000 (Box 73, Folder 2)
    - Shipping Records (June-July 2000), 2000 (Box 73, Folder 3)
    - Shipping Records (August-October 2000), 2000 (Box 73, Folder 4)
    - Shipping Records (November-December 2000), 2000 (Box 73, Folder 5)
    - Shipping Records (January-February 2001), 2000-2001 (Box 73, Folder 6)
    - Shipping Records (March-April 2001), 2000-2001 (Box 73, Folder 7)
    - Shipping Records (May-July 2001), 2001 (Box 73, Folder 8)
    - Shipping Records (August-October 2001), 2001 (Box 73, Folder 9)
    - Shipping Records (November-December 2001), 1999-2001 (Box 73, Folder 10)
    - Shipping Records (January-March 2002), 2001-2002 (Box 73, Folder 11)
    - Shipping Records (April-May 2002), 2002 (Box 73, Folder 12)
    - Shipping Records (June-August 2002), 2002 (Box 73, Folder 13)
    - Shipping Records (September-October 2002), 2002 (Box 73, Folder 14)
    - Shipping Records (November-December 2002), 2001-2002 (Box 73, Folder 15)
    - Shipping Records (January-March 2003), 2003 (Box 73, Folder 16)
    - Shipping Records (April-May 2003), 2003 (Box 73, Folder 17)
    - Shipping Records (June-September 2003), 2003 (Box 73, Folder 18)
    - Shipping Records (October-December 2003), 2003 (Box 74, Folder 1)
    - Shipping Records (January-April 2004), 2003-2004 (Box 74, Folder 2)
    - Shipping Records (April-May 2004), 2004 (Box 74, Folder 3)
    - Shipping Records, Missing Receipts, 2001-2003 (Box 74, Folder 4)
    - Shipping Records, Returned to Consignor, 2004 (Box 74, Folder 5)
    - Shipping Records, Returned to Norma Marin, 2002, June (Box 74, Folder 6)
    - Shipping Records, Works To Be Wrapped for Return, 2004, April (Box 74, Folder 7)
    - Shipping Records, Works Waiting For Pick Up, 2004 (Box 74, Folder 8)
    - Staff Directory, 2000 (Box 74, Folder 9)
    - Stella, Joseph; Drawings, 1981-1994 (Box 74, Folder 10)
    - Stella, Joseph; Price List, 1990 (Box 74, Folder 11)
    - Sugimoto, Hiroshi; Auction Lists, 2003-2004 (Box 74, Folder 12)
    - Telephone, 2000-2002 (Box 74, Folder 13)
    - Travel, American Airlines AAdvantage Program, 2001-2002 (Box 74, Folder 14)
    - Travel, American Express Platinum, 2001 (Box 74, Folder 15)
    - Travel, Delta SkyMiles, 2001 (Box 74, Folder 16)
    - Travel, Promotions and Frequent Flyer Records, 2001-2002 (Box 74, Folder 17)
    - Website; Administrator's Manual, 2003 (Box 74, Folder 18)
    - Website Development, 2002 (Box 74, Folder 19)
  - Financial Records, 1981-2004, 6.2:
    Found are financial records related to the gallery's operation including accounting records, bank deposit records, invoices for gallery expenses, records of payments to consignors, receipts, and tax records.
    - Accounts Receivable/Accounts Payable, 1999 (Box 74, Folder 20)
    - Accounts Receivable/Accounts Payable, 2000 (Box 74, Folder 21)
    - Accounts Receivable/Accounts Payable, 2001-2003 (Box 74, Folder 22)
    - Accounts Receivable/Accounts Payable, Notes, circa 1999-2001 (Box 74, Folder 23)
    - Accounting Records, Miscellaneous, 2002-2003 (Box 74, Folder 24)
    - Accounting Statements, RTY Fine Arts, Inc., 1991 (Box 74, Folder 25)
    - Accounting Statements, RTY Fine Arts, Inc., 2000-2003 (Box 74, Folder 26)
    - Bills, 2003, April-August (Box 74, Folder 27)
    - Deposits, 2000-2001 (Box 74, Folder 28)
    - Deposits, 2002 (Box 74, Folder 29)
    - Deposits, 2003, (2 folders) (Box 74, Folder 30-31)
    - Financial Reports, 1989-1999 (Box 74, Folder 32)
    - Invoices (1980s), 1981-1985, (5 folders) (Box 74, Folder 33-37)
    - Invoices (1980s), 1981-1985, (6 folders) (Box 75, Folder 1-6)
    - Invoices (2000), 2000 (Box 75, Folder 7)
    - Invoices (2001), 2001-2002, (22 folders) (Box 75, Folder 8-29)
    - Invoices (2001), 2001-2002, (6 folders) (Box 76, Folder 1-6)
    - Invoices (2002-2003), 2002-2003, (12 folders) (Box 76, Folder 7-18)
    - Invoices, Framing/Restoration of Richard T. York Photograph Collection, 1996-1999 (Box 76, Folder 19)
    - Louisiana Bank and Trust Company, 1983-1985 (Box 76, Folder 20)
    - Memberships, 1981-1985 (Box 76, Folder 21)
    - Monthly Disbursements and Reconciliation, 2003 (Box 76, Folder 22)
    - Payments to Consignors, 2002 (Box 76, Folder 23)
    - Payments to Consignors, 2003 (Box 76, Folder 24)
    - Payments to Consignors, 2004 (Box 76, Folder 25)
    - Petty Cash, 1984-1985 (Box 76, Folder 26)
    - Receipts (1999), 1999 (Box 76, Folder 27)
    - Receipts (2001), 2001-2002 (Box 76, Folder 28)
    - Receipts (2002), 2002-2003, (2 folders) (Box 76, Folder 29-30)
    - Receipts, Travel, 2002 (Box 76, Folder 31)
    - Robert Mapplethorpe Photographs, 1997-1998 (Box 76, Folder 32)
    - Tax Payments, 2001-2002 (Box 76, Folder 33)
    - Tax Payments, 2003 (Box 76, Folder 34)
    - Tax Preparation Records, 1999 (Box 76, Folder 35)
    - Tax Preparation Records (2001); Richard York Personal, 2000-2002 (Box 76, Folder 36)
    - Tax Preparation Records (2002); Richard York Personal, 2002-2003 (Box 76, Folder 37)
    - Tax Returns, 1995-1999 (Box 76, Folder 38)
    - Tax Returns (2003), circa 2004 (Box 76, Folder 39)
    - Tax Returns, Corporate, 1994-2000 (Box 76, Folder 40)
    - Tax Returns (1987-1992); Richard York Personal, 1987-1992 (Box 76, Folder 41)
    - Tax Returns (1993-1999); Richard York Personal, 1993-1999 (Box 77, Folder 1)
    - Tax Returns, Miscellaneous; Richard York Personal, 1988-1991 (Box 77, Folder 2)
- Printed Materials, 1980-2004, Series 7:; (Boxes 77-78; 1.1 linear feet)
  Printed Materials contains advertising tear sheets from 1998-2002, exhibition catalogs, magazine and newspaper clippings of reviews and announcements, and other miscellaneous printed materials.
  Folders are arranged alphabetically by type of materials. The original arrangement of advertising tear sheets and press books has been maintained.
  - Advertising Tear Sheets, Antiques, 2002, (Folder 1 of 10) (Box 77, Folder 3)
  - Advertising Tear Sheets, Antiques, 2001, (Folder 2 of 10) (Box 77, Folder 4)
  - Advertising Tear Sheets, Antiques, 2000, (Folder 3 of 10) (Box 77, Folder 5)
  - Advertising Tear Sheets, Antiques, 1999, (Folder 4 of 10) (Box 77, Folder 6)
  - Advertising Tear Sheets, Antiques, 1998, (Folder 5 of 10) (Box 77, Folder 7)
  - Advertising Tear Sheets, Art News, 2002, (Folder 6 of 10) (Box 77, Folder 8)
  - Advertising Tear Sheets, Art News, 2001, (Folder 7 of 10) (Box 77, Folder 9)
  - Advertising Tear Sheets, Art News, 2000, (Folder 8 of 10) (Box 77, Folder 10)
  - Advertising Tear Sheets, Others, circa 1998-2002, (Folder 9 of 10) (Box 77, Folder 11)
  - Advertising Tear Sheets, Art and Auction, 1998, (Folder 10 of 10) (Box 77, Folder 12)
  - Clippings; Richard York Personal, 1999 (Box 77, Folder 13)
  - Clippings; Steve Wheeler [Photocopies], 1999 (Box 77, Folder 14)
  - Exhibition Announcements, 2002-2003 (Box 77, Folder 15)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, Richard York Gallery, 1980-1989, (2 folders) (Box 77, Folder 16-17)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, Richard York Gallery, 1990-1999, (5 folders) (Box 77, Folder 18-22)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, Richard York Gallery, 2000-2004, (3 folders) (Box 77, Folder 23-25)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, Other Galleries, 1986, 1996-2003, (2 folders) (Box 77, Folder 26-27)
  - Goldyne, Joseph, 1996-2002 (Box 77, Folder 28)
  - Press Book: William Scharf, 2004, (Folder 1 of 8) (Box 77, Folder 29)
  - Press Book: John Marin and Paul Strand, 2003-2004, (Folder 2 of 8) (Box 77, Folder 30)
  - Press Book: Ted Faiers, 2003-2004, (Folder 3 of 8) (Box 77, Folder 31)
  - Press Book: John Marin, 2003, (Folder 4 of 8) (Box 77, Folder 32)
  - Press Book: John William Hill, 2003, (Folder 5 of 8) (Box 77, Folder 33)
  - Press Book: Peter Lyons, 2003, (Folder 6 of 8) (Box 77, Folder 34)
  - Press Book: Dorothy Ruddick, 2003, (Folder 7 of 8) (Box 77, Folder 35)
  - Press Book: 19th Century Art, 2003, (Folder of 8) (Box 77, Folder 36)
  - Press Book: "Great Planes", 2002-2003, (Folder 1 of 10) (Box 78, Folder 1)
  - Press Book: Edwin Hale Lincoln, 2002, (Folder 2 of 10) (Box 78, Folder 2)
  - Press Book: John Graham, 2002, (Folder 3 of 10) (Box 78, Folder 3)
  - Press Book: "Century of Nature," 2002, (Folder 4 of 10) (Box 78, Folder 4)
  - Press Book: Walter Beck, 2002, (Folder 5 of 10) (Box 78, Folder 5)
  - Press Book: "Movement," 2001-2002, (Folder 6 of 10) (Box 78, Folder 6)
  - Press Book: Steve Wheeler, 2001, (Folder 7 of 10) (Box 78, Folder 7)
  - Press Book: Lockwood De Forest, 2001, (Folder 8 of 10) (Box 78, Folder 8)
  - Press Book: Houghton Cranford Smith, 2001, (Folder 9 of 10) (Box 78, Folder 9)
  - Press Book: "John Marin: The Painted Frame," 2000, (Folder 10 of 10) (Box 78, Folder 10)
- Scrapbooks, 1981-2002, Series 8:; (Boxes 78, 80; 1.0 linear feet)
  Eight scrapbooks document the activities of the Richard York Gallery, Richard York, and the gallery's exhibitions from 1981-2002. Materials include clippings, correspondence, photographs, exhibition catalogs, announcements, and invitations. Scrapbooks were disassembled and materials were kept in their original order.
  Folders are arranged chronologically.
  - Richard York Gallery Scrapbook (1981-1985), 1981-1985, (2 folders) (Box 78, Folder 11-12)
  - Richard York Gallery Scrapbook (1985-1989), 1985-1989 (Box 78, Folder 13)
  - Richard York Gallery Scrapbook (Winter 90-Spring 92), 1990-1992, (2 folders) (Box 78, Folder 14-15)
  - Richard York Gallery Scrapbook (Spring 92-Spring 94), 1992-1994, (2 folders) (Box 78, Folder 16-17)
  - Richard York Gallery Scrapbook (1994-1997), 1994-1997, (Oversized material housed in Box 80) (Box 78, Folder 18)
  - Richard York Gallery Scrapbook (1997-1999), 1987, 1994-1999, (2 folders) (Box 78, Folder 19-20)
  - Richard York Gallery Scrapbook (June 1999-Present), 1999-2000 (Box 78, Folder 21)
  - Richard York Gallery Scrapbook (October 2000- ), 2000-2002, (2 folders) (Box 78, Folder 22-23)
  - Richard York Gallery Scrapbook (1994-1997), 1994-1997, (2 folders, Oversized material from Box 78, Folder 18) (Box 80 (sol), Folder 1-2)
- Photographic Materials, 1977-2004, Series 9:; (Boxes 78-79; 1.2 linear feet)
  Photographic Materials includes color photographs, transparencies, and digital prints, as well as over 600 slides of artwork, primarily works of art which were sold or consigned by the gallery. Artists for which there is significant volume of transparencies include Houghton Cranford Smith and Lockwood de Forest, Sr. Also found is scattered printed materials about artists.
  Folders are arranged alphabetically by subject. Folder dates are based on the print date of the material in the folder.
  - The Art Show, 2003 (Box 78, Folder 24)
  - The Art Show, 2004 (Box 78, Folder 25)
  - Art Shows, 1999-circa 2004 (Box 78, Folder 26)
  - Berninghaus, Oscar Edward, circa 1981-2004 (Box 78, Folder 27)
  - Bierstadt, Albert, 1977 (Box 78, Folder 28)
  - Blashfield, Edwin Howland, circa 1981 (Box 78, Folder 29)
  - Goldyne, Joseph, 1993 (Box 78, Folder 30)
  - Lincoln, Edwin Hale, circa 2001-2003 (Box 78, Folder 31)
  - [Marin, John?]; Portraits, circa 1990s (Box 79, Folder 1)
  - Marin, John; Transparencies (Not in Artbase), circa 2001-2003 (Box 79, Folder 2)
  - Peale, James, circa 1981-2004 (Box 79, Folder 3)
  - Richard York Gallery, circa 1981-2004 (Box 79, Folder 4)
  - Stella, Joseph, circa 1981-2004 (Box 79, Folder 5)
  - US Artists Art Show, 2002 (Box 79, Folder 6)
  - Works of Art, Files Not Found, circa 1990s-2002 (Box 79, Folder 7)
  - Works of Art, Miscellaneous, circa 1981-2004 (Box 79, Folder 8)
  - Works of Art, Miscellaneous, 2000 (Box 79, Folder 9)
  - Works of Art, Miscellaneous, circa 2001 (Box 79, Folder 10)
  - Works of Art, Miscellaneous, circa 2001-2003, (8 folders, includes unmarked metal key and unlabeled microcassette tape) (Box 79, Folder 11-18)
  - Works of Art, Not on File, circa 2001-2003 (Box 79, Folder 19)
  - Works of Art, Slides, 1981-circa 2004, (4 folders, 624 slides) (Box 79, Folder 20-23)
  - Works of Art, We Do Not Have Pix, circa 2001-2003 (Box 79, Folder 24)
  - York, Richard; Slides by Paul Hyman, circa 2000-2003 (Box 79, Folder 25)